clearleft.com 2006-10-25

# Privacy policy | Clearleft Web Design and Accessibility Consultants

This privacy statement covers the website www.clearleft.com.

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact [Richard Rutter](mailto:rich@clearleft.com) or telephone +44 (0)845 838 6163.

##  Information Collection and Use

###  Information Collection

Clearleft Ltd is the sole owner of the information collected on the Clearleft website. We collect information from our users at several different points on our website.

###  Log Files

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

##  Communications from the Site

###  Customer Service

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and about issues relating to their account. We reply via email or phone. 

##  Sharing

Clearleft does not pass on or sell information about our customers to any other business or organization. The only exception to this is wherewe are legally obliged to do so to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

### Business Transitions

In the event Clearleft Ltd goes through a business transition users will be notified via a prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users' personally identifiable information will be used differently from that stated at the time of collection they will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section.

###  Choice/Opt-out

Users who no longer wish to receive promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email, or email us at [info@clearleft.com](mailto:info@clearleft.com), telephone on +44 (0)845 838 6163, or write to Clearleft Ltd, 8 Bristol Gardens, Brighton, BN2 5JR, UK.

### Links

Our website contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website.

### Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and email address), and business information. Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Users' personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties. 

### Security

Our website takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, their information is protected both online and off-line.

All our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users' information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment 

### Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the by emailing [info@clearleft.com](mailto:info@clearleft.com).

### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. 

### Contact Information

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us by phone on +44 (0)845 838 6163, by email on [info@clearleft.com](mailto:info@clearleft.com) or by post at 8 Bristol Gardens, Brighton, BN2 5JR, UK.
